Forged in Darkness, Born in Flames
Firebreather is a fantasy, animation, action film directed by Peter Chung.
It's not easy being a teen like Duncan.
His mom wants him to pay more attention to his homework, while his dad - a 120-foot-tall
monster known as a Kaiju - wants him to become the next King of All Monsters.
When these worlds collide, Duncan must use his human wits and his Kaiju powers - including super strength, agility
and the ability to breathe fire - to protect his family and friends from a giant monster rampage.
Margaret Rosenblatt (voice), played by Dana Delany.
Duncan Rosenblatt (voice), played by Jesse Head.
Kenny Rogers (voice), played by Dante Basco.
Ms. Dreakford (voice), played by Grey DeLisle.
Barnes (voice), played by Reed Diamond.
Steve (voice), played by Billy Evans.
Firebreather is an American animated CGI superhero television film, based on the Image Comics comic
book series of the same name, which premiered on November 24, 2010, on Cartoon Network.
It was directed by Peter Chung from a screenplay by James Krieg based on a story of Phil Hester and Andy Kuhn, and stars the
voices of Jesse Head, Dana Delany, Kevin Michael Richardson, Reed Diamond, Dante Basco, Tia Texada, and Amy Davidson.
The film explores themes of fire, based on comic, dragon.
The tone is intense.